Tonight , president trump's midterm blitz
Our first term was phenomenal
But our second term is blowing everything away
Rallying the faithful and reliably red stas
Pressure over high prices
mounts new cbs polling on the mood of voters
With the mid terms fast approaching and control of congress at state
This as mortgage rates surge
I'm a keiko fujita in los angeles
Borrowing rates near three year high
What it means for buyers
Sellers and the economy
Also tonight
fight for life
I'm
Matt gutman in au dai
with new details about that fly dubai
Cockpit attack and new questions about possible security
Failures that nearly led to a catastrophe
Campus reckoning corn's president breaks his silence
What happened to jane doe in twenty twenty four is deeply disturbing
I'm
Lily elliciano in ethica
New york were a firestorm threatened to engulf the university and local authorities
Over their handling of the alleged fraternity rate
Case
october scorcher i'm . meteorologist andrew kozak
A heat wave is breaking records in the west
While raising the wildfire thread when relief may be
Insight , all that plus a new search to find amelia earhart takes flight
I'm lana zac and west lafayette in indiana in the hanger once used by the legendary amelia earhart
Why these satellite images may finally unlock the mystery of her disappearance
This is the cbs weekend news from new york with girica duncan
Good evening and thank you for joining us
We begin with breaking news
The us air force has rushed to withdraw all twelve b one bombers from an air base in britain
It happened with unusual speed this weekend
Following what the new york times reports as new threats of an iran battack against the allied air base
Last week , six men were arrested in connection to a suspected terror attack against the installation
The pentagon says all the bombers have returned to their home bases in the u
S tonight . there are new questions about the apparent security failure that almost led to catastrophe on that fly
Dubai jet liner
Israel now describes the copilot attacker as a lone wolf extremist
Cbs is matt gutman is in abu dabbi tonight with the very latest matt derrica
That copilot who allegedly tried to crash flight
Ten seventy three from dubai to tel aviv
is being interrogated here in the uae
As cbs news has learned that israel now believes he was acting alone
The copilot suspective trying to crash flight
ten seventy three from dubai to tel aviv
Was likely not directed by a terrorist group or a nation
Israeli sources tell us tonight
And now for the first time
Hero captain spit much chair recounts his version of what the uae now calls a terrorist act
He spoke by phone with israeli prime minister benjamin a
Tyahoo on saturday night
While he was spraying
Uh , out of respect
i was just
At the front and not at the back
And suddenly there was a big load to the back of my head
My first thought was , uh
There was a catastrophic damage to the aircraft
But then after that the blue book kept coming one up to the other
And that's when i realize that it's not the agram ti
The other guy who was in the cockpit with me
Rain for you
The uae says the copilot used the cockpit crash acts to attack the captain
And we've now learned that copilot hamam a hamai
Had been barred from flying by the national carrier of his own country , oman
Due to his extremist views
It's unclear fly dubai was aware of the allegations
And israel revealing this weekend that it received a flight manifest with the names of all the passengers and crew
Yet allowed the flight to proceed to tel aviv
Israeli dentist doctor showto messiah rushed to treat captain matcher's wounds
But also spoke to copilot ahamami
And after two minutes ago he said to me
Uh , kill me , kill me
He said , kill me , kill me
Yes
Multiple times , yes , yes
And had that plane crashed
It would have been the worst aviation disaster in israeli history
And as the euphoria from this averted disaster fades
Both israel and the uae are now facing mountain
Questions about what are being called significant security failures to rica
Matt gutment force tonight , thank you
Today russia kept up its daylight attacks on ukraine's capital of kev
This was the fourth straight day drones
Hit bridges and other critical infrastructure in the city
One person was killed , sixteen others wounded
The attacks came as germany's chancellor made a surprise visit to kive in this country
A mass shooting in georgia today killed two men and left thirty five people h
It happened at a block party in the town of viana
About two hours south of atlanta
Police say shots were fired at two locations
So far no arrests have been made
Well , this weekend cornell university's
President addressed the schools handling of the alleged gang
Rape of a junior at a fraternity house two years ago
Cbs is lilia luciano is in ithica new york with the latest developments
lilia
Good evening ! jrica cornell university conducted a monthlong investigation that resulted in two students being expelled
Two were suspended
At least two were found not to be responsible for sexual assault
None of them face criminal charges
What happened to jane doe in twenty twenty four is deeply disturbing
Cornell university president michael cotlaov
finally broke his islands
About the alleged gang rape of a student at the ki fi fraternity in october twenty twenty four
It raises heartbreaking and troubling issues about sexual assault
And aspects of party culture
He promised more transparency amid growing anger and distrust over the university's handling of the case
Survivors need to know that when they come forward with their stories , somebody will listen
Thomas jeffer represents je doe
Oh , it's most certainly , i believe , was the cover up
The alleged victim left cornell and last month filed the lawsuit against the university
The fraternity and seven of its members
One of them , gielio lopez , was confronted by a student on campus
Were you in the group chat
action yeah and none of you did
You're in the locity man
In twenty twenty four , the district attorney declined to bring charges
Late last week , new york governor kathy hokle tapped attorney general litia james to investigate president trump
Wade in on james's appointment
I feel badly for whoever she's looking at
Because they won't get a fair shake
I don't think this is a political case
It's becoming one
I hope not
It's about a woman who was raped and abused
It's not nothing to do with politics
Jane doe's attorney says she has received thousands of messages of support
She has also received threats . people have threatened him
As well as students who have spoken out in support of jane doe
As well as the accused and some of their attorneys
To rica , lilia , luciano and ithica . new york tonight
Thank you
pressure is building on president trump to address the cost of living with americans
Frustrated with his handling of the economy and rising prices
A new cbs news poll finds
Seventy percent say the president's policies are making the cost of food and groceries go up
Sixty four percent say the war in iran is making oil and gas prices a lot higher
Cbs is torian small is at the white house with motorian jerrica
Good evening
president trump hit the campaign trailed this weekend amid a disappointing jobs report
And a sinking approval rating for his handling of the economy
President trump on the road again in ohio
Before that , alabama , oklahoma , texas all reliably restates at every stop the same ask
Vote republican like he's on the ballot
If the republicans win
You will leach have five thousand dollars in your pocket
And economic success for our country like we have never seen this
But that payout not approved by congress
And a new cbs sings pose suggests that pitch isn't landing either
Just thirty nine percent of americans approve of the president's job performance
Sixty six percent disapprove of how he's handling the economy
And when voters think about the economy
Ninety one presents say it comes down to one thing
The calls for food and everyday services
By the price of everything just keeps going up
And people can't afford their lives
The president also urging republicans to vote by mail
Now in a video he posted on social media this weekend
After years of calling the practice corrupt
Vote early , vote by mail or vote in person on election day
So it's rain terms
iran will never have 看那个开始
No mention of the cost of the iran war
Or the price americans pay at the pump
He knew it was gonna elevate energy prices in the short run
He said , i'm gonna take a hit there
The president is back on the road tomorrow , traveling to nebraska
Another republican strong code jika torian small at the white house
Thank you ! right now mortgage rates are on the rise
And that is pushing down housing sales
Cbs is a keiko fujita and los angeles explained seko
Jerrica mortgage rates are now at three year high
As they were falling before the war with iran
following government that are pushing home ownership out of reach
The hurdles to homeownership keep getting higher
You have your bedrooms on the upper level
And in la realtor tracy doe is seeing smaller crowds at our open houses
To what extent has traffic slowed down for you
Quite a bit
Yeah , a lot . over half of the number of the people that had normally come in a few weeks ago
You know , the numbers are down by half over half
this week . the raid on the thirty year
Fixed surge to seven point five seven percent
A three year high
for perspective buyers that adds two hundred
Eighty three dollars to a monthly mortgage payment for a medium priced home
But it's not all bad news
you have fewer other buyers
Right now in the market
Because they're seeing those same sticker shock of what the mortgage is gonna cost you
And as a result you're gonna probably have in many markets a little bit more negotiating powers
Zero's chief economist misha fisher
What are some of the incentives that you're seeing in the negotiations
Well
So in the negotiations
i think a lot of home builders are also offering rate by down
So that you don't have to pay the market rate on your mortgage
Right now you can get something a little bit cheaper
fisher says he's seen the emergence of dual shoppers
Buyers who start searching on zilla with the intent to buy
But switch to rentals after seeing prices
the hope is to save a little more
While they wait for rates to drop
Jrica a . kiko fujita forced tonight in los angeles
Thank you , tennessee .'s head of prisons
Frank strada has resigned days after the botched execution of christoppike last wednesday
Pikes survived two lethal doses of the drug pinto barbital
She remains unconscious in a nashville hospital
The west is scorching from a heat wave in october that's right october
This weekend the heat fueled of fast
Moving wildfire near santa clarita , california , prompting evacuation orders
And in san francisco , people headed to golden gate beach for a little relief
Let's check in with meterologist andrew kozak for more
Andrew , good evening
It good evening jrica , keep in mind
By the way , places like san francisco
not beach whether typically this time of year october
Only in the low seventies that's what we should be
Instead we have heat advisories
Extreme heat warnings
Totally nearly thirty seven million people under heat alerts
And it doesn't go away today or tomorrow
It stays with us for a good portion of the upcoming week
It's also very windy , hot and dry for places like wyoming and montana
Red flag warnings means that fires can easily start and spread
So that's another thing that we're gonna be watching very closely over the
Course of the next twenty four to forty eight hours
Why is this happening
Well , we've got a heat don't remember that it's in place with the air
Really starting to warm up
As it sinks pass the wind around
That air of high pressure comes off the land
So there's no water or sea breeze to keep any of these points cool
So instead we've got fifteen to twenty degree
Temperatures above average triple digits for l
A over toward bakersfield
This continues for the next couple of days
Derrica , maybe , maybe a little bit of relief
By the time we get to thursday and friday
We shall see andrew kozak , thank you
Straight ahead country superstars zach bryant breaks a stadium record
Why the t shirt he was wearing is also getting attention
But first this story i'm lana zac and west lafayette , indiana
Why a team of researchers here at purdue
believe they've solved the mystery of ammalia earhart's disappearance
Nearly ninety years after a plane was lost over the pacific ocean
Coming up on the cbs
we can use
Tonight a new expedition is underway
Hoping to solve one of aviation great mysteries
The disappearance of amelia earhart
As cbs is lana zac reports
The trail blazing aviator vanished over the pacific nearly ninety years ago
Attempting to circumnavigate the globe
A video air heart makes her second attempt to go around the world of the equator
A global sensation
Amelia earhart was the queen of the air
Contemplated cars cowers about twenty seven thousand miles
But in nineteen thirty seven
As she attempted to become the first person to fly around the world at the equator
Earhart and her navigator fred noonan vanish
The battleship colorado and the carrier lexington were pressed . the duty u
S military teams launched a search
But it ended after sixteen days
Earhart and noon presume to have plunged into the pacific
These are the phoenix islands
And right in the middle of that is nicomuro island
Richard pedigree from the archaeological legacy institute has his own hypothesis
She would have landed her plane here
And probably camped on the island nearby
Pedigree believes earhart and nowon survived on nicomuro island
On this speck of land in the pacific
Items from the nineteen thirty s were found
As were human skeletal remains
But like earhart , they were also lost
The latest clues ? satellite photos of the island
Pedigree thinks this object is earhart's lockheed electroplane
That definitely looks like it could be a play
Joining the expedition
Steve schultz , senior vice president at purdue university
Where earhart was a lecturer
We owe it to amelia's legacy at purdue to follow the evidence
Her belongings still on display at the university's archive
What is it about amelia earhart that it's still so resonant
I think it was what she stood for
Not just in terms of aviation
But a pioneer for women
To this day , so many still look up to her
Philadela is turning right cross land departure to the east
Like wendy rover of the ninety nine
The organization of women pilots earhart helped establish
Which now has chapters around the world
She wanted to let the world know that women can fly
And we're still doing that
Rover says while she's flying
She's constantly thinking about safe places to land
She imaginair heart was too
As she flew over the vast pacific
Amelia earhart was out there
She was going through that exact same thing
So yeah , what happened
What did happen
I would love to know
Not merely solving one of history's most elusive mysteries
This mission honors one of the world's greatest female pioneers
Lana's ac cbs news west lafayette in indiana
still ahead on the cbs weekend news
Flying high in new mexico will take you there
A new record for country music superstar zach bryant
He broke the attendance record at gillette stadium saturday night
Performing for over seventy three thousand fans
Brian did it while wearing a free palestine t shirt
Last month , rapper maclemoore was removed as an opening act at the stadium for ed sharon
It followed maclemore's outspoken support for palestinians
And what stadium owner robert craft called a quote
Broader history of antithematic rhetoric
Today , a change of command in space
Nasa astronaut jessica mer handed over control of the international space station to a russian cosmonaut
Mir and three other crew members are now preparing to return back to earth
The group shared what they described as a huggle
A combination of a hug and a huddle
This weekend , dozens of colorful balloons took flight in albuquerque , new mexico
The annual fiesta features more than five hundred aircraft
Most swords , some had bumpy starts
They came in all shapes and sizes
Including fan favorites darth vader and yoda
Next on the cbs weekend news beavers in london
It's happening no , for real
But first i look back at this day in history
Three figures and about washmore memorial in the heart of south dakotto's back hills
There it is , the sixty foot head of george washington
Action today by a federal grand jury
Looking into the mota million dollar religious empire known as ptl and founder jim baker
i can't figure out what we've done wrong
Finally tonight london has gotten wild
In our weekend journal , cbs is lee and ii reports
It's turned to a toothy rodent to help solve a uniquely urban problem
You weren't kidding when you said it was right next to mcdonald's to find london's wilderness
You take a left at the shopping mall and go under the highway
What lies ahead is home two wild beavers
The first to live here for four hundred years
Any time from now you could see a beaver swimming across the lagoon here
Vet and conservationist dr shawn mcmac brought the beavers to solve a problem
For decades there's been flooding nearby
A tube station is underwater every time flash rainfall comes
And local leaders were about to dish out
They had planned a lot of engineering
Works to create reservoirs and hold more water
And we said beavers could do that at a fraction of the cost and maybe more effectively
So three years ago
A family of beavers was released into west london
And they got beavering
Chopping downwood
Building seven dams and filling three ponds to retain more water
The industrious animals are famous for engineering
We joined the nightly beaver safari
Hoping to catch a glimpse ourselves
The beavers haven't just stopped the flooding
Three years after the family was brought in here . wildlife is thriving
New species have emerged and they even bred kits
Little beaver babies
We just spotted one
Do you see this working in other places in the world and other cities in the world
Absolutely
Yeah
It's , you know , tried and tested over and over again
If we learn to live alongside this
Species coexists and harness all of its benefits
We could be much better off
Especially with climate change challenges
And they make people smile
You know , for future proofing the city
London just leaves it to beavers
Lee and i recbs news london
Hey , if it's working , why not
Well , that is a cbs weekend news for this sunday
I'm . jrica duncan in new york
We thank you so much for watching
Have a great week